Nezir Zahirovic

Living – **Lombok, Indonesia**Born - Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina
nezir.zahirovic@gmail.com
https://www.rubyonrails.ba
https://bosnia-aspnet.blogspot.com
https://www.javascript.ba

https://github.com/nezirz

Likes: ruby javascript reactjs deno ruby-on-rails

Technical Skills

Dislikes: php database

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - contractor - THE WORLD'S FINEST CLUBS Jun 2020 → Current ruby, ruby-on-rails, jruby, sass, docker, mysql, salesforce, stripe-payments

Working on current (old site) by updating part of the site's front end. Also, analyzing the current site architecture and current problems for writing documentation for a new project where I am working on building the new site from ground up with latest ruby 2.7 and rails 6.0.3 versions of language and framework and new modern design. Site will be built with many additional functionalities and also with upgraded current functionalities which exists on current (old site). There will be implemented new custom CMS with few levels of site customization and administration for different levels of users and members.

Backend Rails developer - Fuse Universal

May 2021 → Feb 2022

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, mysql, docker, rspec, cucumber, auth0

April 2022 → Aug2022

Working on set of web projects built with old rails stack 4.1 by implementing new features and fixing various type of bugs. At first place I signed contract for 1 month, and after that we extended 4 time more so in total I worked for Fuse around 13 months.

Freelance contractor Ruby On Rails full stack developer – Elgar Group Ltd postgresql, docker, rspec, haml, javascript

 $Apr 2020 \rightarrow Dec 2021$ ruby, ruby-on-rails,

Working with Ruby, Ruby On Rails, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Docker, Haml, Css, CircleCl tech stack on Ruby On Rails web site https://www.givey.com/

It's an online fundraising platform which is in process of integrating new functionalities. New Strip paying options and fixing bugs and upgrading RSpec tests.

Full stack Ruby On Rails contractor – Netguru Feb $2021 \rightarrow Apr 2021$ ruby, ruby-on-rails, ruby-on-rails-4, javascript, docker, jira, scrum

Work on upgrade an old ruby on rails app built with ruby 2.4.2 and rails 4.2.8 and upgrading it to ruby 2.5.1 and rails 5.0.7 having in mind future upgrade to rails 5.2 and 6.1

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - A Place for Mom

Nov 2020 → Jan 2021

ruby, ruby-on-rails-4, javascript, jquery, postgresql, amazon-web-services, amazon-s3, slim, terraform, kanban, jira

Work as full time ruby on rails developer on 10 projects. Main work role was to fix bugs, deploy code and do upgrades and changes on old ruby on rails tech stack.

Experience

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - contractor - $\underline{Corcovado}$ Jul 2020 \rightarrow Oct 2020 ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, eos, eosio, eosiojs, webflow, jquery, postgresql

Building prof of concept web site for selling, buying, sending trees on a blockchain. Sites main goal is to make it more user friendly than more complicated blockchain usage of wallet in making transactions. Using the site, user use classic username or email and password as login and in the backend site logic makes automatic signing for blockchain transactions as sending trees, buying trees, listing transactions, updating public/private keys, updating user email/password. Very interesting and working concept with usage of eosio js library and also using ruby eosrb gem with custom upgrade specifically for the purpose of this site.

Freelance contractor Ruby On Rails full stack developer – $\underline{2iltd.com}$ Apr 2018 \rightarrow Jun 2020 ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, postgresql, vue.js, css, circleci, amazon-ec2

Worked on project https://v2.crowdfind.com/ as offshore remote resource by fixing previous bugs and development of new functionalities.

Main task was Ruby On Rails project side development by adding new functionality. Refactoring site Search code and upgrading Search functionality to provide Advanced Searching options. Work on adding new Reporting capabilities. Also, adding new sections on web project called Tasks which was new part of web site provided for creating and managing Tasks. Replacing and refactoring custom Vue.Js and Ember.Js JavaScript from few independent forms to plain Vanila JavaScript and jQuery code. Worked with deployment by using CircleCl service. Also, managed AWS EC2 instances of deployed projects.

Freelance contractor Ruby On Rails full stack developer – Monochrome Ltd Jul 2017-Dec 2019

rubyon-rails, javascript, sass, postgresql, ruby, css, responsive-design, docker, sinatra

Worked on Sinatra - framework Ruby web application developed for integrating modular web page/form for collecting user experience on various websites. Analyzed project bottlenecks and worked on code upgrade and optimization.

Freelance contractor Ruby On Rails full stack developer – <u>Balloon Online</u> Jul 2017 \rightarrow Aug 2019 ruby, ruby-on-rails, css, javascript, twitter-bootstrap, postgresql, responsive-design

Worked on maintenance and development of new functionality on web projects balloononline.org and validatestartup.com. Refactored JavaScript/front end code side of the project with latest ECMA Standards. Worked on upgrades of Ruby programming language to a newer version. Also, did upgrade of Rails framework version.

$\textbf{Ruby On Rails full stack developer - contractor} - \underline{Commercial\ Charge} r$

 $Jun\ 2017 \rightarrow Oct\ 2017\ ruby,\ ruby-on-rails,$

postgresql, nginx, puma, websocket, deployment, ubuntu

Work as contractor on web project for Commercial Charger built with Ruby On Rails and Postgresql.

Worked on administration side of the project which was Startup Idea for building e-charging stations for electric vehicles. Spend lot of time on process of deploying project to Ubuntu Server 18.04 and configuring DB PostgreSQL, Nginx and Apache Servers.

Interesting project for administering number of Electrical charging pump stations.

Full Stack Asp.Net developer – <u>LearningLibrary</u>

Apr 2013 → Sep 2017

.net, asp.net, c#, css, jquery, javascript, xml, sql, responsive-design

The Learning Library education platform and solutions for educators and organizations.

Worked with .NET, Asp.Net, C#, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, XML, SQL, Responsive-design Worked on developing new and upgrading old websites. Everyday using the latest MVC .NET technology and also old Web Forms.

Worked on designing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and also backend developing with C#. One of the roles is also to work with the bunch of MSSQL databases and tables.

Servicing more than 50 websites built with first version of ASP to latest MVC Asp.NET from 2017.

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - Ruby On Rails Bosnia Jun 2016 → Dec 2016 ruby, ruby-on-rails, sqlite, css, jquery

Work on creating Community Web Site with latest Ruby On Rails technology stack.

Site is a place which we use as central for saving shortcuts to various post/articles and other information about Ruby programming language and Rails as Web framework.

Sites collected over 5000 shortcut links and more then 7.500.000 page views.

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - contractor – <u>Freelance</u>r *Jun 2016* → *Nov 2016* c#, asp.net, jquery, javascript, sql, twitter-bootstrap, css, ruby-on-rails, ruby

Worked on project http://www.meinforo.de/ web site for comparing article prices and providing suggestions for product best value of price and quality. Main task was in fixing front end () and back-end bugs. Upgrading logic behind scrapping data online.

Ruby On Rails full stack developer - contractor – $\underline{IRS.SE}$ Apr 2015 \rightarrow Nov 2015 ruby, ruby-on-rails, postgresql, jquery, javascript

Building internal project management web application with Ruby On Rails and PostgreSQL. Using Bootstrap, jQuery, Sass and CSS for responsive design.

Implementing full stack development of administration panel with specific functionalities required by the web app and client requests.

CEO and Software Developer – IzumWeb d.o.o.

Oct 2012 → Jul 2013

.net, c#, css, sql-server, mysql, jquery, php, wordpress, opencart

Worked as CEO and head developer for a Danish software company local Bosnian branch. My job was to hire new developers by screening/interviewing. Also, teaching them because there were mostly beginners. There was a lot of office work handling meetings, reporting and work also on specific software development tasks.

Managing company and personal. .net programming and transferring knowledge to younger team colleagues.

Software Developer – AuthorityPartners Dec 2010 Apr 2013 net, sql-server, css, jquery, xslt, xml, winforms

Worked as experienced .NET, C# developer with primarily focus on ASP.NET, MVC, jQuery,CSS tech stack. Worked on Outsourced project built for biggest USA Banking Institutions (JPMorgan Chase, NationStar, WellsFargo). The project was about bank loan management. It was constructed with many configuration options using XML and XSLT document formats. Also, did some work on client side with JavaScript code refactoring and upgrading to specific jQuery library version.

Freelance Android Developer - Private

Aug 2010 → Jun 2012 java, eclipse, paintshop

Worked as freelance Android developer. Worked on implementing few private gaming ideas. In that period, I had built 7 games/apps which had more than 300.000 downloads. Spent lot of time learning Java development.

Independent Consultant for Application Software – Sunrise

Apr 2009 → Sep 2010

.net, vb.net, php, sql-server, reporting

Worked as Independent Consultant Application Software as ASP.NET 3.5 for local micro-credit firm which had more than 50 offices and few hundreds of employees.

As .NET developer my main task was to work on upgrade of existing internal web sites and generating custom MSSQL reports for specific needs for different company branches.

C#, ASP.NET Developer - logosoft

.net, c#, asp.net, sql-server, javascript, iptv

Mar 2008 → Feb 2009

Worked for local ISP provider and Education Company.

Worked as .NET, ASP.NET developer on a project building firs local IPTV software platform which is in use for cable TV's. My task was to reprogram all functionalities of TV Remote controller for communication with that days modern Set Top boxes. It was one of my favorite projects. Mainly worked in JavaScript.

C# Developer, MOSS 2007, WSS 3.0 Administrator - DNC

Apr 2007 → Mar 2008

.net, asp.net, sharepoint, sharepoint-2007

Worked with .NET and Sharepoint tech stack on internal projects for company. Also, done few implementations of Sharepint 2007 for international clients. Worked on deployment and configuration of Sharepoint services MOSS 2007, WSS 3.0. Done some Sharepoint web part developments.

C# Developer (beginner) – Smarter Software Solutions Aug 2006 → Feb 2007 c#, sql-server

Worked for Austrian company in a local Bosnian branch office on creating desktop application to communicate with Sharepoint services 2.0 and later 3.0.

Main task was as a part of a team-built C# desktop application. And learning about company processes.

Political Science - University of Sarajevo social, sciences

Sep 1998 → Dec 2002

Education

MCPD

asp.net

2009 → Current

Certifications

quiz.rubyonrails.ba - https://quiz.rubyonrails.ba

Feh 2023 → Current

ruby, ruby on rails, programming, quiz, chatgpt, coding, knowledge, challenges

My latest rails project built with latest rails and ruby versions 7 & 3.2.

It's a knowledge quiz with around 400 various questions about ruby and ruby on rails, generated with ChatGPT.

All questions are generated by Al and also all answers correct and misleading.

I did additional checkup and did small updates in case of few questions which were not so clear.

In a few first day of publishing the quiz site collected more than 50 plays with more than 80 games finished.

Quiz allows single player game mode where you can play one of 11 different games levels and also you can play a game. After you finish a game, you can invite friends to play the same question set you played and at the end you can compare results

Also, there are integrated Certificates and Score diploma for sharing on social networks.

Had a Talk on Ruby on Rails Global Summit 2023 - https://events.geekle.us/ruby/

Jan 2023

I held a presentation on a theme:

"Its 2023 and hiring interviews are still messy. Can we as (Ruby On Rails) community make them better?" Here is my part of the video which can be accessed via the following: link: https://www.youtube.com/live/UCdVBOJI3Ow?feature=share&t=2976

blog.rubyonrails.ba – https://blog.rubyonrails.ba

Dec 2022 → Current

ruby, ruby on rails, programming, recruiting, interviewing

My latest blog where I am writing more about work, experiences, interviews, recruiting and in general expressing my thoughts about different things.

Projects & Interests

Ruby Webshot Gem – https://rubygems.org/gems/ruby_webshot ruby

Dec 2019 → Dec 2019

Ruby Webshot gem will make nice webshots for you. I needed the webshot/screenshot functionality for one of my website and after trying few ruby gems currently available I found that they are not updated lately and that they are using depricated version of PhantomJS: 'webshot' [https://github.com/vitalie/webshot] 'screenshot' [https://github.com/amire80/screenshot]. Also, I had an issue with produced image CSS formating when I used webshot gem. So, I decided to start building a gem for myself and to share for anyone who need something like this. The Ruby Webshot Gem use latest Webdrivers.

sum_strings Gem - https://rubygems.org/gems/sum_strings

Oct 2018 → *Oct 2018* ruby

With this gem you are able to sum array of strings values. Primary ment for summing array of hours in format ["20:25","10:10"].strings_to_sum(':') which will result as "30:35" hours/minutes.

url_shortener - https://github.com/nezirz/url_shortener ruby

Nov 2015 Dec 2015

Simple Ruby On Rails Web Site for creating SHORT URL from LONG ones!

RubyLeetSpeak Gem – https://github.com/nezirz/RubyLeetSpeak Nov 2015 → Nov 2015 ruby

Ruby leet (1337) speak. Leet (or "1337"), also known as elect or leetspeak, is an alternative alphabet for the English language that is used primarily on the Internet. It uses various combinations of ASCII characters to replace Latinate letters. For example, leet spellings of the word leet include 1337 and 133t; elect may be spelled 31337 or 3133t.

 ${\color{red} random_cases} \ {\color{red} Gem} - \underline{{\color{blue} https://github.com/nezirz/random_cases}}$

 $Nov 2015 \rightarrow Nov 2015 \text{ ruby}$

Simple implementation of String method in Ruby for randomizing characters in string or text.

blog.rubyonrails.ba – *December 2022* - ruby 3.1.2 rails 7.0.4

Created my new blog with latest ruby on rails versions with a goal to write more about stack.

Public Artifacts

JavaScript Bosnia - http://www.javascript.ba/

Sep 2018

javascript, jquery, ruby-on-rails, postgresql, twitter-bootstrap, devise, rails-admin

Creator and owner of JavaScript.ba tech news site. Built with Ruby On Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, Postgresql, Bootstrap, Sass.

Nov 2016

Ruby On Rails Bosnia – https://www.rubyonrails.ba/ rubyonrails, javascript, sql

Creator and owner of Ruby On Rails Bosnia. Ruby and Rails community web site.

.NET, ASP.NET, C#, METEOR JS, RUBY ON RAILS,VB.NET, MS SQL, JQUERY, CSS – http://bosnia-aspnet.blogspot.com/

Jan 2009

Personal blog about everyday work in technologies like: C# Asp.Net CSS MSSQL JavaScript jQuery Bootstrap Ruby Ruby On Rails.

Apps & Software

android

The simplest counting game ever 'The Numbers' Game goal is to count as much as you can. There are numbers intervals for example: Easy: Counting start from 2 so next will be 3, 4, ...

Idea and programming.

$\begin{tabular}{lll} \textbf{Android Time Tracker} & | \textbf{SlideME} - \underline{\text{http://slideme.org/application/android-time-tracker}} \\ android & | \textbf{Android Time Tracker} \\ | \textbf{Andr$

Android Time Tracker 2.0 (ATT) Is your precious time companion. With ATT you can track all your activities. ATT is very useful for people who need to track yours every day...

Idea and programming

Who am I 3 | SlideME - http://slideme.org/application/who-am-i-3 android

WHO AM I 3 NEW NOW FREE!!! After big success of my first quiz game "Who am I" (free version) more than a 2 000 download for first 5 days. We decide to create a commercial version...

Idea and programming

Who am I | SlideME - http://slideme.org/application/who-am-i android

This is little android application made for fun. You need to make guess who is a person on the picture. The game catch is to make much more guess in selected time period 30,60...

Idea and programming ...

EU Anthems | SlideME – http://slideme.org/application/eu-anthems

EUNA (European Union National Anthems) android application. EUNA is very useful android application for all of you who want to know a European Union Anthem sound & lyrics. It is...

Idea and programming...

World Anthems | SlideME – http://slideme.org/application/world-anthems android

WORLD NATIONAL ANTHEMS World National Anthems FREE is our new application which is the most comprehensive Android applications on the market in terms of content-type of world...

Idea and programming ...

Socijala.xyz – https://socijala.xyz/ Sep 2019 ruby, ruby-on-rails-6, bootstrap-4, jquery, javascript, postgresql, responsive-design

Private social network twitter looks like. Implemented posting, membership, following, likes, dislikes, comments/sub comments likes/dislikes, blocks, anonymous posting, commenting, sub commenting, scheduled feed from interesting sources, sites, twitter, YouTube... still in development.

porezi.info – https://porezi.info/ Aug 2018 ruby-on-rails, ruby, javascript, jquery, postgresql, materialize, twitter-bootstrap Simple site with administration for calculating and generating PDF government required form for freelancers Tax in Bosnia.

selfies.vip – https://selfies.vip/

Jun 2018

 $ruby-on-rails,\ ruby,\ javascript,\ jquery,\ postgresql,\ twitter-bootstrap,\ materialize,\ css,\ responsive-design$

My own web app for sharing a selfie and getting rewards for the most liked selfie.

Designed for with materialize css primarily for a mobile device.

After 3 months of running already gathered more than 2000 members.

First Computer: i386 siemens

Tools

Favorite Editor: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, RubyMine, Sublime, Notepad++